<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="hello">Hello World, AndroidDashboardDesignActivity!</string>
    <string name="app_name">ITICU23</string>
    <string name="sosyal">Sosyal Arenada ITICU</string>
    <string name="hakkimizda">Our university, located in the centre of Istanbul, one of the major culture capitals of the world, offers education with the awareness of meeting with the world, carrying several millennia of accumulation of scientific, historical and cultural heritage into the future.

 

Founded by the Istanbul Chamber of Commerce Education and Social Services Foundation, Istanbul Commerce University started formal education in 2001-2002 Academic Year. Our university is not only committed to keeping pace with the modern age but also inculcating in our students the virtues of our deep-rooted culture as well as the validity-reliability principles of art and science in a way that transcends spatial or temporal boundaries.

 

As one of the first foundation universities of Turkey, our university managed to capture the attention of students in a short period through its academic stance, quality of its programs, qualifications of scholars, technical equipment and its vision regarding the future. Having 73 students at its very first year, Istanbul Commerce University has achieved to have over 5000 students and 169 scholars in its 10th year. The prestige of the university, gained over a very short span of time, is maintained thanks to the hundreds of international and national publications, the awards given in various fields, and the activities carried out.

 

Another leading factor which gives our university distinction and high standing is the fact that its three campuses are located in central and prestigious parts of Istanbul, one of the culture capitals of the world. Besides making transportation convenient, this peculiar location of the university enables one to be a dynamic innovative pioneer, keeping pace with modern age, expanding into the world and extending towards the future abreast of culture, science as well as economics.

 

The three campuses of Istanbul Commerce University are in Uskudar, Kucukyali and by the Golden Horn coast in Eminonu, the heart of the city. The University holds the privilege of being an academic institution situated in Eminonu, just by the coast of the historical peninsula, in the centre of commercial facilities. This location is particularly noteworthy as it enables us to follow cultural, scientific and economic developments closely.

 

Modern world is undergoing a process of globalization in which the boundaries between theory and practice as well as the ones between subject and object have become transparent. What is more, in today’s global world, spatial and temporal differences have lost their significance. Under such circumstances, with its qualified academic staff, well aware of scientific and technological advancements, Istanbul Commerce University is committed to offer a universal style of education, integrating theory and practice as required. 

 

Istanbul Commerce University acknowledges the fact that it is essential to adopt a holistic perspective to keep abreast of technological and scientific advancements which gain momentum every day. Hence, within the framework of international agreements, some university students are offered the opportunity of studying abroad and some foreign students are welcomed through exchange programs.

 

Preserving authenticity and self identity within the globalization process will only be possible through scientific thinking. This way of thinking enables us to grasp the world, come up with well-qualified knowledge that will lead to social transformation by employing information processes and tools for producing knowledge. Being aware of such requirements and principles, Istanbul Commerce University reflects a contemporary, inquisitive and conscientious understanding that stems from values inherited from its particular geography and civilization, shedding light on new horizons of the future. For all these reasons, the University is constantly expanding and strengthening its international network.

 

Istanbul Commerce University considers its students as individuals who can assume the responsibilities required by the society and the era. Focusing on intensive practical training, the University places value on enabling students to be equipped with globally competitive practical, business and people skills. It is also important that the graduates be employed in all levels of public and private enterprises. While contributing to science through projects and publications, the University updates its education programs regularly so as to make up the qualified labor force of the society. Exploiting the opportunities brought by information technologies, Istanbul Commerce University aims at following, interpreting and testing science and technology at an international level.   

 

Istanbul Commerce University aims at educating young people who understand the era and value freedom of thought and participation, with awareness of international competition  and facing the world, who develop with the society, business life and production processes, possess high professional skills, share with others and are broad-minded. For this purpose, Istanbul Commerce University is investing in the scientific future of the country with its five Faculties, English Preparatory School and Vocational School as well as Institutes of Social Sciences, Physical Sciences and Foreign Trade. Faculty of Arts and Sciences includes Departments of Statistics, Mathematics, Psychology and Pedagogy. Faculty of Commercial Sciences includes Departments of Banking and Finance, Business Administration, Tourism Management, International Relations, International Trade, and Economy.

 

Faculty of Law, which has achieved an outstanding quality-level among foundation universities includes Departments of Public Law, and Private Law.

 

Faculty of Communication consists of Departments of Visual Communication Design, Public Relations, and Media and Communication Systems.

 

Faculty of Engineering and Design contains Departments of Computer Engineering, Industrial Engineering, Interior Architecture and Environmental Design, and Fashion and Textile Design, Mechatronics Engineering, Electric and Electronic Engineering, Jewelry Engineering. The faculty attaches importance to cooperation with the industry in activities of training and research and, by using the resources of the information age optimally, gives an education which is effective, continuously open-to-change, and up-to-date with technological developments.

 

The Vocational School consists of Departments of Computer Technology and Programming, Accounting, Marketing, Logistics, Foreign Trade, Computer-Assisted Publishing,  Ground Handling Services Management in Aviation, Aviation Logistics, and Double Diploma Program conducted with Hackney College.

 

All sections of the community are provided with the opportunity of education at every level by the Continuing Education Centre with certificate programs which have a specified goal of supplying individual, institutional, social and cultural development as an excellent example of lifelong education. In addition to these, along with our Career Planning Centre, the Application and Research Centre of Intellectual Property and Rival Business Law, which has a rising popularity in the banking world,  will come into service soon.

 

European Union Research and Application Centre contributes to the development of application and research projects with its projects and studies in the process of membership to the European Union. Our center performs benefiting from EU financial aids which are obtained to strengthen the relations among universities in EU member countries. The Centre contributes to projects realized by other institutions with its academic staff using the facilities provided by our university as well. Istanbul Commerce University gives support to Turkey in its process of EU Membership in accordance with its  establishment philosophy.

 

The TOEFL Centre, one of our prestige units, is located on the Eminönü Campus and offers ETS-licensed, internet-based TOEFL exams at the TOEFL Test Centre. Two specially-designed labs for TOEFL IBT Exams are operational in the Centre.

 

Health Services Unit and Psychological Counseling Centre serve students with physical and psychological problems. Handicapped Student Unit trying to present education opportunities to disadvantaged students under better conditions. Our rich library, extended on three campuses, supplies services to academic staff, students and researchers with its domestic and foreign databases, electronic journals and books.

 

As a reflection of civil society in universities, Istanbul Commerce University stands at the top, with its 54 Student Clubs providing academic, social and cultural services. The university carries on the periodic publication of two journals in the field of social sciences and one in physical sciences.

 

Istanbul Commerce University, , with the Board of Trustees and the Rector, both appointed by Istanbul Chamber of Commerce Education and Social Services Foundation,  is moving into the future with confident and determined steps, feeling behind itself the support and contributions of Istanbul Chamber of Commerce,  the fourth biggest Chamber in the world.</string>
</resources>